<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="admin_inter.css" type="text/css" charset="UTF-8"?>
<XML>
<TITLE> </TITLE><Heading-1>
<A ID="pgfId-1038002"></A>
<A ID="51820"></A>
Administrative Interface</Heading-1>
<pagenum>
<A ID="pgfId-1038146"></A>
15</pagenum>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1038003"></A>
The MarkLogic Server administrative interface (or Admin Interface) is used to configure the MarkLogic Server software on your system. This chapter provides a general overview of the Admin Interface and includes the following sections:</Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1041553"></A>
<A href="admin_inter.xml#id(49127)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Overview of the Admin Interface</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1041568"></A>
<A href="admin_inter.xml#id(69619)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Accessing the Admin Interface</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1041573"></A>
<A href="admin_inter.xml#id(78920)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Logging Off the Admin Interface</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1041578"></A>
<A href="admin_inter.xml#id(41142)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Creating and Managing Administrators</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1041557"></A>
<A ID="49127"></A>
Overview of the Admin Interface</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1038004"></A>
With the Admin Interface, you can complete any of the following tasks:</Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1038005"></A>
Manage basic software configuration</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1038006"></A>
Create and configure groups</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1038007"></A>
Create and manage databases</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1038008"></A>
Create and manage new forests</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1038009"></A>
Back up and restore forest content</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1038010"></A>
Create and manage new web server and Java-language access paths</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1038011"></A>
Create and manage security configurations</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1038012"></A>
Tune system performance</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1038013"></A>
Configure namespaces and schemas</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1041687"></A>
Check the status of resources on your systems</Body-bullet>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1038014"></A>
The Admin Interface is implemented as a MarkLogic Server web application. By default, it runs on port 8001 of your hosts. If you have completed the basic tasks in the <Emphasis>
Getting Started with MarkLogic&#160;Server</Emphasis>
 manual, then accessing the Admin Interface requires that you enter a user name and password. After you have been authenticated, you should not need to re-enter your user name and password to complete any of the other tasks outlined in this guide during the current session.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1038015"></A>
Some configurations changes require the server to restart to reflect the changes. Configuration changes that do not require the server to restart to reflect the changes are defined as 'hot'. In an Enterprise Edition clustered deployment, 'cold' tasks will require all of the hosts in the cluster to restart their instance of MarkLogic Server in order to reflect the changes. In an Enterprise Edition single-server deployment and in all Standard Edition deployments, 'cold' tasks will cause MarkLogic Server to restart in order to reflect the changes. For a list of which tasks are 'hot' and which are 'cold,' see <A href="hotcold.xml#id(84238)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Appendix A: ‘Hot' versus ‘Cold' Admin Tasks' on page&#160;277</A>.</Body>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1038016"></A>
<A ID="69619"></A>
Accessing the Admin Interface</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1045743"></A>
Only authorized administrators can log into the Admin Interface. An authorized administrator is a user who has the <code>
admin</code>
 role. Authorized administrators have access to all administrative tasks in MarkLogic Server; therefore, authorized administrators are trusted personnel and are assumed to be non-hostile, appropriately trained, and follow proper administrative procedures. </Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1045747"></A>
To access the Admin Interface, complete the following procedure:</Body>
<Number1>
<A ID="pgfId-1038018"></A>
Open the following URL in a browser:</Number1>
<Code>
<A ID="pgfId-1038020"></A>
<Hyperlink>
<A href="http://localhost:8001/" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://localhost:8001/</A></Hyperlink>
</Code>
<Note>
<A ID="pgfId-1038021"></A>
If you are not accessing the Admin Interface from the same system on which MarkLogic Server is running, you will have to use the IP address or domain name of the server instead of <code>
localhost</code>
.</Note>
<NumberList>
<Number>
<A ID="pgfId-1038022"></A>
Log in with your admin user name and password. The summary screen for the Admin Interface displays.</Number>
</NumberList>
<Note>
<A ID="pgfId-1038024"></A>
If you have already logged on as an admin user during this session, you do not have to log in again.</Note>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1041724"></A>
From the summary screen, you can see and click on many of the items configured in MarkLogic Server. The summary screen displays all of the Databases, App Servers, Groups, Forests, Security objects, and Hosts configured for your system. If you click on any object or category, the Admin Interface takes you to a more detailed page for the object or category.</Body>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1038025"></A>
<A ID="78920"></A>
Logging Off the Admin Interface</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1038026"></A>
To log off the Admin Interface, close the browser window used to access the Admin Interface. This action is sufficient to end the current session and force the user to authenticate again starting another session.</Body>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1038027"></A>
<A ID="41142"></A>
Creating and Managing Administrators</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1038028"></A>
MarkLogic Server administrators are managed by defining which user has the <code>
admin</code>
 role. Users with the <code>
admin</code>
 role, known as authorized administrators, are trusted personnel and are assumed to be non-hostile, appropriately trained, and follow proper administrative procedures. For the procedures for creating, managing and removing administrators, see <A href="security.xml#id(73923)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Security Administration' on page&#160;187</A>. </Body>
</XML>
