<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="intro.css" type="text/css" charset="UTF-8"?>
<XML>
<TITLE> </TITLE><Heading-1>
<A ID="pgfId-1040426"></A>
Requirements and Database Compatibility</Heading-1>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1077522"></A>
This chapter introduces MarkLogic Server, lists the product requirements and supported platforms, and describes the database compatibility with previous releases. It includes the following sections:</Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077526"></A>
<A href="intro.xml#id(79579)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Introduction</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077574"></A>
<A href="intro.xml#id(11335)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Memory, Disk Space, and Swap Space Requirements</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077579"></A>
<A href="intro.xml#id(63469)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Supported Platforms</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077584"></A>
<A href="intro.xml#id(80903)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Upgrades and Database Compatibility</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1077516"></A>
<A ID="79579"></A>
Introduction</Heading-2>
<pagenum>
<A ID="pgfId-1073154"></A>
10</pagenum>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1040427"></A>
MarkLogic Server is a powerful software solution for harnessing your digital content base. MarkLogic Server enables you to build complex applications that interact with large volumes of content in XML, SGML, HTML and other popular content formats. The unique architecture of MarkLogic Server ensures that your applications are both scalable and high-performance, delivering query results at search-engine speeds while providing transactional integrity over the underlying content repository. MarkLogic Server Enterprise Edition can be configured for a distributed environment, enabling you to scale your infrastructure through hardware expansion.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1077552"></A>
This document describes how to install MarkLogic Server on your system. It covers both Enterprise and Standard Edition on all supported platforms. It is intended for a technical audience, specifically an IT staff with experience in XML. </Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1040433"></A>
This installation guide explains the procedures needed to install MarkLogic Server on your system. This document only explains how to install the software, not how to use the software. To learn how to get started using the software, see the following documents (available on <Hyperlink>
<A href="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">developer.marklogic.com</A></Hyperlink>
):</Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1040440"></A>
<Emphasis>
Getting Started With MarkLogic Server</Emphasis>
</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1070745"></A>
MarkLogic Server <Emphasis>
Administrator's Guide</Emphasis>
</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1070749"></A>
MarkLogic Server <Emphasis>
Application Developer's Guide</Emphasis>
</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1082148"></A>
MarkLogic Server <Emphasis>
Search Developer's Guide</Emphasis>
</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1070769"></A>
<Emphasis>
MarkLogic XQuery and XSLT Function Reference</Emphasis>
</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1081669"></A>
MarkLogic Server <Emphasis>
Release Notes</Emphasis>
</Body-bullet>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1040441"></A>
<A ID="11335"></A>
Memory, Disk Space, and Swap Space Requirements</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1040442"></A>
Before installing the software, be sure that your system meets the following requirements:</Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1040443"></A>
512 MB of system memory, minimum. 2 GB or more recommended, depending on database size. If you plan to deploy the full data set for the Oscar sample application bundled Application Builder on a 32-bit Microsoft Windows XP system, you should have at least 3GB of system memory. </Body-bullet>
<Body-indent>
<A ID="pgfId-1081775"></A>
The first time it runs, MarkLogic Server automatically configures itself to the amount of memory on the system, reserving as much as it can for its own use. If you need to change the default configuration, you can manually override these defaults at a later time using the Admin Interface.</Body-indent>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1082248"></A>
3 times the disk space of the total forest size. Specifically, each forest on a filesystem requires its filesystem to have at least 3 times the forest size in disk space. This translates to three times the disk space of the source content after it is loaded.</Body-bullet>
<Body-indent>
<A ID="pgfId-1040446"></A>
For example, if you plan on loading content that will result in a 10 GB database, reserve at least 30&#160;GB of disk space. The disk space reserve is required for merges. </Body-indent>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077208"></A>
On UNIX systems, swap space at least equal to the amount of physical memory on the machine. Swap space equal to twice the amount of physical memory is highly recommended.</Body-bullet>
<Body-indent>
<A ID="pgfId-1077209"></A>
For example, if you have a UNIX machine with 32&#160;GB of memory, you should ideally configure the swap space to be 64&#160;GB (and at least 32&#160;GB). This is true on Windows systems also, but the system is normally set up to grow the swap (page) file as needed.</Body-indent>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1081845"></A>
On Linux systems, MarkLogic recommends setting Linux Huge Pages to 3/8 the size of your physical memory. For details on setting up Huge Pages, see <Hyperlink>
<A href="http://magazine.redhat.com/2007/05/29/how-do-i-set-up-hugepages-in-red-hat-enterprise-linux-4/" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://magazine.redhat.com/2007/05/29/how-do-i-set-up-hugepages-in-red-hat-enterprise-linux-4/</A></Hyperlink>
. </Body-bullet>
<Body-indent>
<A ID="pgfId-1081891"></A>
If you have Huge Pages set up on a Linux system, your swap space on that machine should be twice the size of your physical memory minus the size of your Huge Page (because Linux Huge Pages are not swapped). For example, if you have 64GB of physical memory, and if you have Huge Pages set to 24 GB, then you need swap space of 80 GB ([64&#160;-&#160;24]&#160;x&#160;2).</Body-indent>
<Body-indent>
<A ID="pgfId-1081911"></A>
At system startup on Linux machines, MarkLogic Server logs a message to the <code>
ErrorLog.txt</code>
 file showing the Huge Page size, and the message indicates if the size is below the recommended level.</Body-indent>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1073116"></A>
<A ID="63469"></A>
Supported Platforms</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1073120"></A>
MarkLogic Server is supported on the following platforms:</Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1081651"></A>
Microsoft Windows Server 2008 (x86), Microsoft Windows 2003 Server (x86), Microsoft Windows XP SP2, Microsoft Windows Vista 32-bit Edition (x86)*</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1081652"></A>
Microsoft Windows Server 2008 (x64), Windows 2003 Server 64-bit Edition (x64), Windows Vista 64-bit Edition (x64)*</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077501"></A>
Sun Solaris 10 (64-bit SPARC)</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077502"></A>
Sun Solaris 10 (x64)</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077503"></A>
Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5 (x86)** ***</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077504"></A>
Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5 (x64)** *** ****</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1082307"></A>
CentOS 5 (x64)** *** </Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1082451"></A>
Mac OS X 10.6*****</Body-bullet>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1081787"></A>
* Microsoft Windows Vista is supported for development only. 
If MarkLogic Server fails to start up on Windows with the error 'the application failed to initialize properly (0xc0150002)', then a dependency is missing from your environment and you need to download and install one of the following DLLs:
32-bit versions of Windows require the DLL at the following link: <Hyperlink>
<A href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=200B2FD9-AE1A-4A14-984D-389C36F85647&amp;displaylang=en" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=200B2FD9-AE1A-4A14-984D-389C36F85647&amp;displaylang=en</A></Hyperlink>
. 
64-bit versions of Windows require the following DLL: <Hyperlink>
<A href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=eb4ebe2d-33c0-4a47-9dd4-b9a6d7bd44da&amp;DisplayLang=en" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=eb4ebe2d-33c0-4a47-9dd4-b9a6d7bd44da&amp;DisplayLang=en</A></Hyperlink>
.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1081636"></A>
** The deadline I/O scheduler is required on Red Hat Linux platforms. The deadline scheduler is optimized to ensure efficient disk I/O for multi-threaded processes, and MarkLogic Server can have many simultaneous threads. For information on the deadline scheduler, see the Red Hat documentation (for example, <Hyperlink>
<A href="http://www.redhat.com/docs/wp/performancetuning/iotuning/iosubsystem-scheduler-deadline.html" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://www.redhat.com/docs/wp/performancetuning/iotuning/iosubsystem-scheduler-deadline.html</A></Hyperlink>
, <Hyperlink>
<A href="http://www.redhat.com/docs/wp/performancetuning/iotuning/iosubsystem-scheduler-selection.html" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://www.redhat.com/docs/wp/performancetuning/iotuning/iosubsystem-scheduler-selection.html</A></Hyperlink>
, and <Hyperlink>
<A href="http://www.redhat.com/magazine/008jun05/features/schedulers/" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://www.redhat.com/magazine/008jun05/features/schedulers/</A></Hyperlink>
).</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1081830"></A>
***The <code>
redhat-lsb</code>
 and the <code>
glibc</code>
 packages are required on Red Hat Linux. Additionally, on 64-bit Red Hat Linux, both the 32-bit and the 64-bit <code>
glibc</code>
 packages are required.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1081807"></A>
****Red Hat Linux 5 (x64) is also supported in a VMWare ESX 3.0.2, ESX 3.5.3, or ESX&#160;4.0 (installed on bare metal) environment.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1082628"></A>
*****Mac OS X is supported for development only. Conversion (Office and PDF) and entity enrichment are not available on Mac OS X. Mac OS X 10.6 (Snow Leopard) is required.</Body>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1082630"></A>
<A ID="80903"></A>
Upgrades and Database Compatibility</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1077569"></A>
MarkLogic Server 4.2 supports upgrades from MarkLogic Server 4.0, MarkLogic Server 4.1, or from MarkLogic Server 4.2-1 or later databases. If you are upgrading from an earlier version of MarkLogic Server, you must first upgrade to 4.0 before moving to 4.2. For the procedure for upgrading to MarkLogic Server 4.0 see <A href="procedures.xml#id(49025)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Upgrading from Previous Releases' on page&#160;11</A>.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1077601"></A>
During the upgrade, the security database and the schemas databases are automatically upgraded. The security database is upgraded with the latest execute privileges and the schemas database is upgraded with the latest version of the schemas used by MarkLogic Server. The upgrade occurs as part of the installation procedure.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1077611"></A>
Databases that contain your own content are also upgraded to work with MarkLogic Server 4.2; once you upgrade to 4.2, you will no longer be able to use that database with MarkLogic Server&#160;4.1 or 4.0. MarkLogic Corporation strongly recommends performing a backup of your databases before upgrading to MarkLogic Server 4.2. </Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1078004"></A>
For the procedure for upgrading to MarkLogic Server 4.2, see <A href="procedures.xml#id(49025)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Upgrading from Previous Releases' on page&#160;11</A>. For details about known incompatibilities between MarkLogic Server 4.0, 4.1, and 4.2, see <A href="../relnotes/chap4.xml#id(_Toc71544047)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Known Incompatibilities with Previous Releases</Hyperlink>
</A> in the <Emphasis>
Release Notes</Emphasis>
.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1078052"></A>
This section contains database compatibility information between various releases, and includes the following sections.</Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1078053"></A>
<A href="intro.xml#id(22819)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
4.2 Database Compatibility With 4.1 and 4.0</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1082097"></A>
<A href="intro.xml#id(57904)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
4.0 Database Compatibility With 3.2</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1081483"></A>
<A href="intro.xml#id(20903)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
3.2 Database Compatibility With 3.1</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1078061"></A>
<A href="intro.xml#id(83846)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
3.1/3.2 Database Compatibility With 3.0</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Heading-3>
<A ID="pgfId-1077984"></A>
<A ID="22819"></A>
4.2 Database Compatibility With 4.1 and 4.0</Heading-3>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1082537"></A>
MarkLogic Server 4.2 databases include improvements compared to 4.1 and 4.0 databases. Therefore, to take advantage of these improvements, you need to reindex your 4.1 or 4.0 databases in 4.2. When you upgrade to 4.2, all databases with <code>
reindex enable</code>
 set to <code>
true</code>
 will automatically begin reindexing immediately. If you do not want the databases to reindex, you must set <code>
reindex enable</code>
 to <code>
false</code>
 <Emphasis>
before</Emphasis>
 upgrading (that is, you must set <code>
reindex enable</code>
 to <code>
false</code>
 in 4.1 or 4.0). You can always reindex your content later by changing this setting back to <code>
true</code>
 after installing MarkLogic Server 4.2.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1082541"></A>
Also, you can reindex your content a little bit at a time by enabling reindexing for a while, then disabling it for a while, then enabling it, and so on. You might want to use this technique to reindex your database during non-peak hours, for example, over a period of hours or days or weeks, depending on how large your database is. Always ensure that you have the proper system requirements, as defined in <A href="intro.xml#id(11335)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Memory, Disk Space, and Swap Space Requirements' on page&#160;5</A>.</Body>
<Note>
<A ID="pgfId-1082548"></A>
If you are upgrading from 4.0 or from 4.1 without Application Builder and you want to install Application Services after you upgrade and start MarkLogic Server, you can add the App Server needed for the Application Services as described in <A href="../appbuilder/intro.xml#id(10407)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Setting Up and Starting Application Services</Hyperlink>
</A> in the <Emphasis>
Application Builder Developer's Guide</Emphasis>
.</Note>
<Heading-3>
<A ID="pgfId-1082055"></A>
<A ID="57904"></A>
4.0 Database Compatibility With 3.2</Heading-3>
<Note>
<A ID="pgfId-1082085"></A>
This section is here for reference only about the compatibility between MarkLogic Server 3.2 and 3.1.</Note>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1082112"></A>
MarkLogic Server 4.0 databases can have several new indexes compared to 3.2 databases. Therefore, to take advantage of these new features, you need to reindex your 3.2 databases in 4.0. When you upgrade to 4.0, all databases with <code>
reindex enable</code>
 set to <code>
true</code>
 will automatically begin reindexing immediately. If you do not want the databases to reindex, you must set <code>
reindex enable</code>
 to <code>
false</code>
 <Emphasis>
before</Emphasis>
 upgrading (that is, you must set <code>
reindex enable</code>
 to <code>
false</code>
 in 3.2). You can always reindex your content later by changing this setting back to <code>
true</code>
 after installing MarkLogic Server 4.0.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1082116"></A>
Also, you can reindex your content a little bit at a time by enabling reindexing for a while, then disabling it for a while, then enabling it, and so on. You might want to use this technique to reindex your database during non-peak hours, for example, over a period of hours or days or weeks, depending on how large your database is. Always ensure that you have the proper system requirements, as defined in <A href="intro.xml#id(11335)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Memory, Disk Space, and Swap Space Requirements' on page&#160;5</A>.</Body>
<Heading-3>
<A ID="pgfId-1082064"></A>
<A ID="20903"></A>
3.2 Database Compatibility With 3.1</Heading-3>
<Note>
<A ID="pgfId-1082058"></A>
This section is here for reference only about the compatibility between MarkLogic Server 3.2 and 3.1.</Note>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1082017"></A>
MarkLogic Server 3.2 and newer databases are language-aware. Details such as stemming and tokenization are different for different languages. For an overview of how languages work in MarkLogic Server, see the 'Languages, Encodings, and Collations' chapter of the <Emphasis>
Application Developer's Guide</Emphasis>
. </Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1081497"></A>
Because of the differences in stemming and tokenization between languages, and because MarkLogic Server allows you to specify languages at the element level, the index data in MarkLogic Server databases contains language-specific information. Additionally, there are other features in 3.2 that require 3.2 (or newer) indexes. </Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1081504"></A>
When you upgrade to 3.2, all databases with <code>
reindex enable</code>
 set to <code>
true</code>
 will begin reindexing immediately. If you do not want the databases to reindex, you must set <code>
reindex enable</code>
 to <code>
false</code>
 <Emphasis>
before</Emphasis>
 upgrading (that is, you must set <code>
reindex enable</code>
 to <code>
false</code>
 in 3.1). You can always reindex your content later by changing this setting back to <code>
true</code>
 after installing MarkLogic Server 3.2.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1081511"></A>
MarkLogic Server 3.2 automatically detects the format of the content in the database. If you do not reindex the content when upgrading to 3.2 (that is, if you set <code>
reindex enable</code>
 to <code>
false</code>
 in your database configuration <Emphasis>
before</Emphasis>
 you install 3.2), then the database will run in compatibility mode, and certain 3.2 features will be disabled (for example, non-English languages and <code>
cts:frequency</code>
 for lexicon values).</Body>
<Heading-3>
<A ID="pgfId-1077979"></A>
<A ID="83846"></A>
3.1/3.2 Database Compatibility With 3.0</Heading-3>
<Note>
<A ID="pgfId-1077628"></A>
This section is here for reference only about the compatibility between MarkLogic Server 3.1 and 3.0.</Note>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1081694"></A>
You can have this same level of compatibility as other versions and 4.0 between 4.0 and 3.0 as well. You must upgrade to MarkLogic Server 3.1 before upgrading to MarkLogic Server 3.2 and 4.0. For details on upgraded from 3.0 to 3.1, see the MarkLogic Server 3.1 <Emphasis>
Installation Guide</Emphasis>
.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1078023"></A>
MarkLogic Server 3.1 and newer has diacritic-aware indexes. MarkLogic Server 3.0 does not have diacritic-aware indexes. Therefore, databases created with 3.0 will have different default behavior in 3.1 in the handling of searches that involve diacritic characters. Additionally, databases created in 3.0 that are not reindexed might miss diacritic-insensitive matches on <code>
cts:search</code>
 operations. Note the following about user-created databases that are upgraded to MarkLogic Server 3.1:</Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077644"></A>
If reindexing is enabled, MarkLogic Server 3.1 will reindex any 3.0 database in order to rebuild the default text indexes as diacritic-insensitive indexes. After the reindex operation is completed, all diacritic searches will work correctly.</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077724"></A>
If reindexing is not enabled, then diacritic searches using MarkLogic Server 3.1 will behave differently against 3.0 databases than 3.1 databases. Any <code>
cts:search</code>
 operations on upgraded, un-reindexed 3.0 databases, with terms that incorporate diacritics (in the search specification or in the content loaded in MarkLogic Server) have the following characteristics: </Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1077742"></A>
If the term passed to <code>
cts:search</code>
 incorporates one or more diacritic characters, and the search is either explicitly or implicitly <code>
diacritic-sensitive</code>
, then the search will work correctly.</Body-bullet-2>
<Body-bullet-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1077647"></A>
If the term passed to <code>
cts:search</code>
 incorporates one or more diacritic characters, and the search is explicitly <code>
diacritic-insensitive</code>
, then the search will not match terms in the source content that had diacritics.</Body-bullet-2>
<Body-bullet-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1077648"></A>
If the term passed to <code>
cts:search</code>
 does not incorporate any diacritic characters, and the search is explicitly <code>
diacritic-sensitive</code>
, then the search will work correctly. </Body-bullet-2>
<Body-bullet-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1077649"></A>
If the term passed to <code>
cts:search</code>
 does not incorporate any diacritic characters, and if the search is implicitly or explicitly <code>
diacritic-insensitive</code>
, then the search will not match terms in the source content that incorporated diacritics (even though you specified <code>
diacritic-insensitive</code>
 matches).</Body-bullet-2>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077651"></A>
If the source content does not incorporate diacritic characters, or if diacritic-related recall is not important to your application, these incomplete search issues may not pose a problem for you. However, you should understand that at any point in the future, if you enable reindexing, the database will undertake this reindexing task concurrently with any other reindexing tasks that may be required. </Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077639"></A>
Note that the database has no way to know whether or not your source content incorporates diacritics, so if reindexing is enabled, it will reindex all the documents in order to ensure that text indexes are diacritic-aware.</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077808"></A>
Any new or changed content will be added diacritic-aware, potentially creating different diacritic behavior for different parts of your content set.</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1077749"></A>
If you choose not to reindex your 3.0 database, and if you always specify the <code>
diacritic-sensitive</code>
 option to <code>
cts:search</code>
, then your results will be the same as they were in MarkLogic Server 3.0.</Body-bullet>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1077761"></A>
</Body>
</XML>
