<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="copyright.css" type="text/css" charset="UTF-8"?>
<XML>
<TITLE> </TITLE><Heading-1>
<A ID="pgfId-998597"></A>
Copyright</Heading-1>
<pagenum>
<A ID="pgfId-1102936"></A>
2</pagenum>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1102954"></A>
&#169; Copyright 2002-2010 by MarkLogic Corporation. All rights reserved worldwide.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1102968"></A>
This Material is confidential and is protected under your license agreement.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1102982"></A>
Excel and PowerPoint are either registered trademarks or trademarks of Microsoft Corporation in the United States and/or other countries. This document is an independent publication of MarkLogic Corporation and is not affiliated with, nor has it been authorized, sponsored or otherwise approved by Microsoft Corporation.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1102996"></A>
Contains LinguistX, from Inxight Software, Inc. Copyright &#169; 1996-2006. All rights reserved. www.inxight.com.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1103010"></A>
Antenna House OfficeHTML Copyright &#169; 2000-2008 Antenna House, Inc. All rights reserved.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1103024"></A>
Argus Copyright &#169;1999-2008 Iceni Technology Ltd. All rights reserved.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1103038"></A>
Contains Rosette Linguistics Platform 6.0 from Basis Technology Corporation, Copyright&#160;&#169;&#160;2004-2008 Basis Technology Corporation. All rights reserved.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1103052"></A>
This product includes software developed by the OpenSSL Project for use in the OpenSSL Toolkit (http://www.openssl.org/) Copyright &#169; 1995-1998 Eric Young (eay@cryptsoft.com). All&#160;rights reserved. Copyright &#169; 1998-2001 The OpenSSL Project. All rights reserved. 
Contains software derived from the RSA Data Security, Inc. MD5 Message-Digest Algorithm. Copyright&#160;&#169;&#160;1991-1992, RSA Data Security, Inc. Created 1991. All rights reserved.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1111999"></A>
Contains ICU with the following copyright and permission notice:
Copyright &#169; 1995-2010 International Business Machines Corporation and others. All rights reserved. Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &quot;Software&quot;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, provided that the above copyright notice(s) and this permission notice appear in all copies of the Software and that both the above copyright notice(s) and this permission notice appear in supporting documentation. 
THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT OF THIRD PARTY RIGHTS. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR HOLDERS INCLUDED IN THIS NOTICE BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, OR ANY SPECIAL INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, OR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION, ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF THIS SOFTWARE. 
Except as contained in this notice, the name of a copyright holder shall not be used in advertising or otherwise to promote the sale, use or other dealings in this Software without prior written authorization of the copyright holder. </Body>
</XML>
