<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="concepts.css" type="text/css" charset="UTF-8"?>
<XML>
<TITLE> </TITLE><Heading-1>
<A ID="pgfId-1043289"></A>
Content Processing Concepts</Heading-1>
<pagenum>
<A ID="pgfId-1043814"></A>
7</pagenum>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1043291"></A>
This chapter describes what content processing is and why it might be interesting to you. This chapter includes the following topics:</Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1043639"></A>
<A href="concepts.xml#id(70693)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Content Processing Defined</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1044414"></A>
<A href="concepts.xml#id(53730)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Problems Content Processing Addresses</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1044407"></A>
<A href="concepts.xml#id(60964)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Example Content Processing Application</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1048081"></A>
<A ID="70693"></A>
Content Processing Defined</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1048232"></A>
Content can go through many stages before it is ready to use in an application. Sometimes, these stages might include making the content well-formed XML, some stages might transform one XML structure to another, and some stages might add (or take away) value to the content by examining the contents and combining it with other content or information. The process of content going from one stage to another is called <Emphasis>
content processing</Emphasis>
.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1048242"></A>
Every document has a lifecycle. The lifecycle of different documents can vary significantly. A lifecycle typically begins when a document is created, and then continues through various stages of content processing; content processing enables a document to move from through the phases of its lifecycle.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1048243"></A>
Content processing can be very simple or extremely complex. You might decide to add a timestamp to a document and define a content processing stage to add the timestamp. You might have a process that translates the text from one language to another. Often, many of these stages combined together form an overall set of content processing work you need to do on a document.</Body>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1044773"></A>
<A ID="53730"></A>
Problems Content Processing Addresses</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1048113"></A>
Content processing addresses a wide range of problems, from altering the structure of a document to modifying its content. While the range of problems content processing can address is virtually unlimited, there are several core content processing capabilities required to address many of these wide-ranging problems: </Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1048355"></A>
The ability to change the content from one form to another.</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1048359"></A>
The ability to tie together different pieces of content processing.</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1048362"></A>
The ability to separate different documents for different types of processing.</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1048364"></A>
The ability to automate the entire procedure so documents can move through complex processing phases automatically.</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1048416"></A>
The ability to integrate manual steps or long-running, asynchronous operations in applications.</Body-bullet>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1048365"></A>
Flexibility is important in content processing, as both the starting points of documents and their end results can vary significantly. Also, application requirements can evolve over time, forcing the content processing application to change with the requirements. It is therefore necessary to have a content processing environment that can allow for such change.</Body>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1048106"></A>
<A ID="60964"></A>
Example Content Processing Application</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1048079"></A>
An example of a content processing application is the Default Conversion Option in MarkLogic Server. The Default Conversion Option takes Microsoft Office, Adobe PDF, and HTML documents and converts them into XHTML and simplified DocBook documents. There are many steps in the conversion process, and all of the steps are designed to execute automatically, based on the outcome of other steps in the process. For more information on the Default Conversion Option, see <A href="default.xml#id(64749)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'The Default Conversion Option' on page&#160;49</A>. </Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1048400"></A>
The Default Conversion Option is one example of a content processing application. There are many other content processing applications you can build, both more complex and less complex than the Default Conversion Option. </Body>
</XML>
