<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="intro.css" type="text/css" charset="UTF-8"?>
<XML>
<TITLE> </TITLE><Heading-1>
<A ID="pgfId-1051062"></A>
Getting Started with MarkLogic Server for EC2</Heading-1>
<pagenum>
<A ID="pgfId-1066854"></A>
5</pagenum>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1067674"></A>
This chapter provides an overview of MarkLogic Server on Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) using a MarkLogic Amazon Machine Image (AMI), as well as how to create an Amazon EC2 account and order a MarkLogic Server for EC2 AMI. This chapter includes the following sections:</Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1063858"></A>
<A href="intro.xml#id(41894)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Understanding MarkLogic Server for EC2</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1067416"></A>
<A href="intro.xml#id(28329)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Summary of Set-up Procedures MarkLogic Server for EC2</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1063872"></A>
<A href="intro.xml#id(52961)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Creating an Amazon EC2 Account</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1063894"></A>
<A href="intro.xml#id(99793)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Ordering a MarkLogic Server for EC2 AMI</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1063960"></A>
For more detailed information on Amazon EC2, see the Amazon documentation located at the following URL:</Body>
<Code>
<A ID="pgfId-1063991"></A>
<Hyperlink>
<A href="http://aws.amazon.com/documentation/" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://aws.amazon.com/documentation/</A></Hyperlink>
</Code>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1063747"></A>
<A ID="41894"></A>
Understanding MarkLogic Server for EC2</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1063649"></A>
MarkLogic provides pre-packaged AMIs containing RightScale CentOS Linux and MarkLogic Server. MarkLogic has included scripts on these AMIs that simplify the steps necessary to get your MarkLogic Server instances up and running.</Body>
<Heading-3>
<A ID="pgfId-1066641"></A>
Amazon EC2 Terminology</Heading-3>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1062248"></A>
The following are the definitions for the terms used in this guide:</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1062249"></A>
<Emphasis>
Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2)</Emphasis>
 is a web service that enables you to launch and manage server instances in Amazon's data centers using APIs or available tools and utilities.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1062250"></A>
<Emphasis>
CentOS</Emphasis>
 is a community-supported, free and open source operating system based on Red Hat Enterprise Linux.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1065873"></A>
<Emphasis>
Amazon Machine Image (AMI)</Emphasis>
 is an encrypted machine image that contains all information necessary to boot instances of software. Instances of MarkLogic Server are created from AMIs.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1064385"></A>
<Emphasis>
Elastic Block Store (EBS)</Emphasis>
 is a type of storage designed specifically for Amazon EC2 instances. Amazon EBS allows you to create volumes that can be mounted as devices by Amazon EC2 instances. Amazon EBS volumes behave like raw unformatted external block devices. They have user-supplied device names and provide a block device interface. You can load a file system on top of Amazon EBS volumes, or use them just as you would use a block device. Amazon EBS volumes exist separately from the actual instances and persist until you delete them. This allows you to store your data without leaving an Amazon EC2 instance running. Each Amazon EBS volume can be up to one TiB in size.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1066490"></A>
An <Emphasis>
Instance</Emphasis>
 is the running system after an AMI is launched. Instances remain running unless they fail or are terminated. When this happens, the data on the instance is no longer available. Once launched, an instance looks very much like a traditional host.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1066494"></A>
An Instance Type defines the size of an Amazon EC2 instance. The MarkLogic Server instance types are shown in the table below.</Body>
<TABLE>
<ROW>
<TH ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellHeading>
<A ID="pgfId-1066558"></A>
Instance Type</CellHeading>
</TH>
<TH ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellHeading>
<A ID="pgfId-1066560"></A>
Description</CellHeading>
</TH>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="2" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1066562"></A>
Standard Instances</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1066564"></A>
Large Instance 7.5 GB of memory, 4 EC2 Compute Units (2 virtual cores with 2 EC2 Compute Units each), 850 GB of local instance storage, 64-bit platform. </CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1066568"></A>
Extra Large Instance 15 GB of memory, 8 EC2 Compute Units (4 virtual cores with 2 EC2 Compute Units each), 1690 GB of local instance storage, 64-bit platform. </CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="2" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1066570"></A>
High-Memory Instances</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1066572"></A>
High-Memory Double Extra Large Instance 34.2 GB of memory, 13 EC2 Compute Units (4 virtual cores with 3.25 EC2 Compute Units each), 850 GB of local instance storage, 64-bit platform. </CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1066576"></A>
High-Memory Quadruple Extra Large Instance 68.4 GB of memory, 26 EC2 Compute Units (8 virtual cores with 3.25 EC2 Compute Units each), 1690 GB of local instance storage, 64-bit platform. </CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1066578"></A>
High-CPU Instances</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1066580"></A>
High-CPU Extra Large Instance 7 GB of memory, 20 EC2 Compute Units (8 virtual cores with 2.5 EC2 Compute Units each), 1690 GB of local instance storage, 64-bit platform. </CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
</TABLE>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1066613"></A>
An <Emphasis>
Instance Store</Emphasis>
 is a fixed amount of storage space for an instance. An instance store is not designed to be a permanent storage solution. If an instance reboots, either intentionally or unintentionally, the data on the instance store will survive. If the underlying drive fails or the instance is terminated, the data will be lost.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1066614"></A>
An <Emphasis>
EC2 Compute Unit (ECU)</Emphasis>
 provides the equivalent CPU capacity of a 1.0-1.2 GHz 2007 Opteron or 2007 Xeon processor.</Body>
<Heading-3>
<A ID="pgfId-1066663"></A>
MarkLogic Server in an EC2 Environment</Heading-3>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1066803"></A>
Using MarkLogic Server as an EC2 service provides you with all of the MarkLogic Server functionality without having to maintain the hardware. In addition your instances of MarkLogic Server can be accessed from anywhere on the internet and you can grow the size of your instances as you roll out new MarkLogic Server applications and expand your user base.</Body>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1066892"></A>
<A ID="28329"></A>
Summary of Set-up Procedures MarkLogic Server for EC2 </Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1067306"></A>
The following is a summary of the procedures described in this guide.</Body>
<TABLE>
<ROW>
<TH ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellHeading>
<A ID="pgfId-1067323"></A>
Procedure</CellHeading>
</TH>
<TH ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellHeading>
<A ID="pgfId-1067325"></A>
For Details See</CellHeading>
</TH>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067327"></A>
If you don't already have an Amazon EC2 account, create one.</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067329"></A>
 <A href="intro.xml#id(52961)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Creating an Amazon EC2 Account' on page&#160;4</A></CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067331"></A>
Order MarkLogic Server for EC2.</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067333"></A>
 <A href="intro.xml#id(99793)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Ordering a MarkLogic Server for EC2 AMI' on page&#160;5</A></CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067335"></A>
Open the Amazon AWS Management Console.</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067337"></A>
 <A href="instance.xml#id(69008)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Accessing the AWS Management Console' on page&#160;6</A></CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067339"></A>
Create a security group to enable HTTP traffic.</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067341"></A>
 <A href="instance.xml#id(69725)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Creating a Security Group' on page&#160;8</A></CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067343"></A>
If you don't already have a key pair, create one.</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067345"></A>
 <A href="instance.xml#id(24571)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Creating a Key Pair' on page&#160;11</A></CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067347"></A>
Create an instance of MarkLogic Server from an AMI.</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067349"></A>
 <A href="instance.xml#id(25305)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Creating an Instance of MarkLogic Server from an AMI' on page&#160;12</A></CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067351"></A>
Create an EBS volume and attach it to your MarkLogic Server instance.</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067353"></A>
<A href="instance.xml#id(81403)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Creating an EBS Volume and Attaching it to an Instance' on page&#160;17</A></CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067355"></A>
Open the MarkLogic Server Admin interface.</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1067357"></A>
 <A href="instance.xml#id(18558)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Accessing the MarkLogic Server Admin Interface' on page&#160;19</A></CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
</TABLE>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1066616"></A>
<A ID="52961"></A>
Creating an Amazon EC2 Account</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1065509"></A>
Before you can order a MarkLogic Server for EC2 AMI, you must set up an Amazon EC2 account. To set up an Amazon EC2 account, go to <code>
<A href="http://aws.amazon.com/ec2" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL"></A></code>
<Hyperlink>
http://aws.amazon.com/ec2</Hyperlink>
 and click Sign Up for Amazon EC2:</Body>
<Body-indent>
<A ID="pgfId-1062701"></A>
<IMAGE xml:link="simple" href="images/signup_ec2.gif" show="embed" actuate="auto"/>
</Body-indent>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1064233"></A>
Then follow the directions to create a new account. You will need to provide email and mail addresses, create a password, and provide credit card information. </Body>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1062648"></A>
<A ID="99793"></A>
Ordering a MarkLogic Server for EC2 AMI</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1064202"></A>
MarkLogic provides public AMIs that make it easy to create a new MarkLogic Server instance running on EC2. You can place an order for a MarkLogic Server for EC2 AMIs from the cloud computing page on the MarkLogic developer site: </Body>
<Code>
<A ID="pgfId-1065547"></A>
<Hyperlink>
<A href="http://developer.marklogic.com/cloudcomputing/" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://developer.marklogic.com/cloudcomputing/</A></Hyperlink>
</Code>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1066261"></A>
Follow the link on the MarkLogic Cloud Computing page to access the Amazon Payments page. An Amazon EC2 account is required to access this page. Here you will find detailed information on pricing and you will have the option to place an order to subscribe to a MarkLogic AMI service. Placing an order allows you to access the AMI from within Amazon's EC2 administration tools. You are not charged any up-front fees. You are only charged for hourly usage of the instances of MarkLogic Server you create. Once you have decided on your order, click Place Your Order:</Body>
<Body-indent>
<A ID="pgfId-1065797"></A>
<IMAGE xml:link="simple" href="images/place_order.gif" show="embed" actuate="auto"/>
</Body-indent>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1063368"></A>
Next you will see a page containing your Activation Key. You will not need the Activation Key, so there is no need to save a copy of the key.</Body>
<Body-indent>
<A ID="pgfId-1065716"></A>
<IMAGE xml:link="simple" href="images/activation_key.gif" show="embed" actuate="auto"/>
</Body-indent>
</XML>
