<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="other.css" type="text/css" charset="UTF-8"?>
<XML>
<TITLE> </TITLE><Heading-1>
<A ID="pgfId-1040610"></A>
<A ID="_Toc71544048"></A>
Other Notes</Heading-1>
<pagenum>
<A ID="pgfId-1043482"></A>
32</pagenum>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1040611"></A>
This section provides the following information about MarkLogic Server:</Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1047340"></A>
<A href="other.xml#id(43648)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Memory and Disk Space Requirements</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1047348"></A>
<A href="other.xml#id(_Toc71544049)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Compatibility with XQuery Specifications</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1047352"></A>
<A href="other.xml#id(_Toc71544050)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
XQuery Extensions</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1047356"></A>
<A href="other.xml#id(_Toc71544051)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Documentation</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1047360"></A>
<A href="other.xml#id(_Toc71544052)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Browser Requirements</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1047371"></A>
<A href="other.xml#id(_Toc71544053)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Support</Hyperlink>
</A></Body-bullet>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1047333"></A>
<A ID="43648"></A>
Memory and Disk Space Requirements</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1047332"></A>
MarkLogic Server requires at least 512 MB of system memory.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1051724"></A>
The first time it runs, MarkLogic Server automatically configures itself to the amount of memory on the system, reserving as much as it can for its own use. If you need to change the default configuration, you can manually override these defaults at a later time using the Admin Interface.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1040613"></A>
MarkLogic recommends the following two guidelines for server sizing:</Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1040614"></A>
Configure your server with 1 GB of physical memory for every 16 GB of source content you expect to manage.</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1040615"></A>
Configure your server with at least one CPU (or core) per 100 GB of source content.</Body-bullet>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1040616"></A>
Pragmatically, we recommend running most configurations with a minimum of two CPUs (or two cores).</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1052086"></A>
MarkLogic Server requires 3 times the disk space of the total forest size. Specifically, each forest on a filesystem requires its filesystem to have at least 3 times the forest size in disk space. This translates to three times the disk space of the source content after it is loaded. For example, if you plan on loading content that will result in a 10 GB database, reserve at least 30&#160;GB of disk space. The disk space reserve is required for merges. </Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1052070"></A>
On UNIX systems, MarkLogic Server requires swap space at least equal to the amount of physical memory on the machine. Swap space equal to twice the amount of physical memory is highly recommended. For example, if you have a UNIX machine with 32&#160;GB of memory, you should ideally configure the swap space to be 64&#160;GB (and at least 32&#160;GB). This is true on Windows systems also, but the system is normally set up to grow the swap (page) file as needed. </Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1051859"></A>
For more details about memory, disk, and swap requirements, see <A href="../install_all/intro.xml#id(11335)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef"><Hyperlink>
Memory, Disk Space, and Swap Space Requirements</Hyperlink>
</A> in the <Emphasis>
Installation Guide</Emphasis>
.</Body>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1040620"></A>
<A ID="_Toc71544049"></A>
<A ID="_Stopping_the_Server"></A>
Compatibility with XQuery Specifications</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1040621"></A>
This release implements the XQuery language, functions and operators specified in the W3C XQuery 1.0 Recommendations:</Body>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1051610"></A>
<Hyperlink>
<A href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xquery/" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://www.w3.org/TR/xquery/</A></Hyperlink>
</Body-bullet>
<Body-bullet>
<A ID="pgfId-1051612"></A>
<Hyperlink>
<A href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xquery-operators/" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://http://www.w3.org/TR/xquery-operators/</A></Hyperlink>
 </Body-bullet>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1051613"></A>
Additionally, there is backwards compatibility with the May 2003 version of the XQuery 1.0 Draft specification used in MarkLogic Server 3.2 and previous versions. For details on the XQuery implementation in MarkLogic Server 4.1, including the three different dialects supported, see the <Emphasis>
XQuery and XSLT Reference Guide</Emphasis>
.</Body>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1051662"></A>
<A ID="_Toc71544050"></A>
XQuery Extensions</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1051663"></A>
Working within the W3C XQuery 1.0 Recommendation, MarkLogic has created a number of language extensions enabling key functionality not supported in the current release of the language specification. These extensions provide transactional update capabilities, assorted search and retrieval features, various data manipulation functions, and administrative tools. </Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1040630"></A>
The extensions, as well as the XQuery standard functions, are documented at <Hyperlink>
<A href="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://developer.marklogic.com</A></Hyperlink>
. </Body>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1040632"></A>
<A ID="_Toc71544051"></A>
Documentation</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1040633"></A>
MarkLogic Server includes the following documentation, available through the support web site and through <Hyperlink>
<A href="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://developer.marklogic.com/</A></Hyperlink>
:</Body>
<TableAnchor>
<A ID="pgfId-1047121"></A>
</TableAnchor>
<TABLE>
<ROW>
<TH ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellHeading>
<A ID="pgfId-1047124"></A>
Documentation</CellHeading>
</TH>
<TH ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellHeading>
<A ID="pgfId-1047126"></A>
Description</CellHeading>
</TH>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047128"></A>
<Emphasis>
Installation Guide</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047130"></A>
Provides procedures for installing MarkLogic Server.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047132"></A>
<Emphasis>
Administrator's Guide</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047134"></A>
Provides procedures for administrative tasks such as creating servers, creating databases, backing up databases, creating users, setting up your security policy, and so on.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1052206"></A>
<Emphasis>
Scripting Administrative Tasks Guide</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1052208"></A>
Provides information on writing code to script various administrative tasks such as creating and modifying databases, App Servers, and so on.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1051878"></A>
<Emphasis>
Application Developer's Guide</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1051880"></A>
Provides procedures, methodologies, and conceptual information about general MarkLogic Server application development tasks.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047136"></A>
<Emphasis>
Search Developer's Guide</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047138"></A>
Provides procedures, methodologies, and conceptual information about search-based application development tasks.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1051896"></A>
<Emphasis>
Application Builder Developer's Guide</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1051898"></A>
Provides step-by step information on using Application Builder to build a search application, and also provides information on customizing applications built with Application Builder. </CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047203"></A>
<Emphasis>
Content Processing Framework Guide</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047205"></A>
Provides an introduction to the Content Processing Framework and procedures for installing the default content processing framework.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047199"></A>
<Emphasis>
Understanding and Using Security Guide</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047201"></A>
Provides information on the role-based security model in MarkLogic Server.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1048226"></A>
<Emphasis>
Query Performance and Tuning Guide</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1048228"></A>
Provides performance-related information that is useful to application developers and administrators.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1051636"></A>
<Emphasis>
Scalability, Availability, and Failover Guide</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1051638"></A>
Provides information on large-scale system architecture, clustering, availability, and details on setting up shared-disk and local-disk failover.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047299"></A>
<Emphasis>
MarkLogic XQuery and XSLT Function Reference</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047302"></A>
API documentation for the MarkLogic built-in and module extensions to the XQuery standard functions, as well as API documentation for the W3C functions implemented in MarkLogic Server.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047310"></A>
<Emphasis>
4.1 Release Notes</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047313"></A>
Contains a summary of new features, upgrade compatible information, and known issues.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047265"></A>
XCC Javadoc and .Net C# API Documentation</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047267"></A>
API documentation for the MarkLogic XML Contentbase Connector for Java API (XCC/J) and .Net XCC C# API documentation.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047140"></A>
<Emphasis>
XCC Developer's Guide</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047142"></A>
An overview of the what you can do with the XCC libraries, examples of how to use XCC, and an overview of the sample applications included with XCC.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047148"></A>
<Emphasis>
XQuery and XSLT Reference Guide</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047150"></A>
A condensed overview of the XQuery language, including information on the three XQuery dialects in MarkLogic Server. This book does include some syntax information, although it is primarily intended as in introduction and quick-reference to the language, not as a comprehensive reference.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
<ROW>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047156"></A>
<Emphasis>
Getting Started with MarkLogic Server</Emphasis>
</CellBody>
</CELL>
<CELL ROWSPAN="1" COLSPAN="1">
<CellBody>
<A ID="pgfId-1047158"></A>
A quick, step-by-step overview of how to get up and running with MarkLogic Server.</CellBody>
</CELL>
</ROW>
</TABLE>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1048281"></A>
XQuery language documentation is provided through the W3C working group drafts specified in <A href="other.xml#id(_Toc71544049)" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="XRef">'Compatibility with XQuery Specifications' on page&#160;30</A>. Sample code is provided through the demo server at <Hyperlink>
<A href="http://localhost:8000/" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://localhost:8000/,</A></Hyperlink>
 which is automatically installed as part of the MarkLogic Server installation process. Additionally, there are many samples available on the MarkLogic developer site (<Hyperlink>
<A href="http://developer.marklogic.com" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://developer.marklogic.com</A></Hyperlink>
).</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1048294"></A>
XQuery language extensions specific to MarkLogic Server are documented online in the <Emphasis>
MarkLogic XQuery and XSLT Function Reference</Emphasis>
. Example code snippets are provided as part of that documentation. The Admin Interface provides a large-scale example of complex XQuery programming, using many of the MarkLogic Server XQuery language extensions. </Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1040637"></A>
The Admin Interface includes built-in help screens that explain the purpose of the various controls and parameters in the Admin Interface. </Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1040640"></A>
Known bugs are documented online as we find them or as they are reported to us. See <Hyperlink>
<A href="http://support.marklogic.com" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://support.marklogic.com</A></Hyperlink>
 (supported customers only) for more details.</Body>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1051973"></A>
<A ID="_Toc71544052"></A>
Browser Requirements</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1051987"></A>
The MarkLogic Server Admin Interface is supported on Internet Explorer 6 or newer and Firefox browsers.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1052164"></A>
Application Builder and the applications generated with Application Builder are supported on Internet&#160;Explorer 6 or 7 on Windows, Firefox 3.0 or newer on Windows, and Safari 3 or newer on Mac OS 10.5. Other browser/platform combinations may work but are not as thoroughly tested.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1051991"></A>
Authentication functions in MarkLogic Server are supported for Internet Explorer 6 or newer and Firefox. </Body>
<Heading-2>
<A ID="pgfId-1040646"></A>
<A ID="_Toc71544053"></A>
Support</Heading-2>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1048306"></A>
MarkLogic provides technical support according to the terms detailed in your Software License Agreement. For evaluation licenses, MarkLogic may provide support on an 'as possible' basis. </Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1048308"></A>
For registered customers, we invite you to visit our support website at <Hyperlink>
<A href="http://support.marklogic.com/" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://support.marklogic.com</A></Hyperlink>
 to access our full suite of documentation and help materials. For all customers, including community licensed customers, visit the MarkLogic Developer's site at <Hyperlink>
<A href="http://developer.marklogic.com" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">http://developer.marklogic.com</A></Hyperlink>
, which includes full product documentation, downloads, and developer community open-source projects.</Body>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1048310"></A>
If you have questions or comments, you may contact MarkLogic Technical Support at the following email address:</Body>
<Body-indent>
<A ID="pgfId-1048312"></A>
<Hyperlink>
<A href="mailto:support@marklogic.com" xml:link="simple" show="replace" actuate="user" CLASS="URL">support@marklogic.com</A></Hyperlink>
</Body-indent>
<Body>
<A ID="pgfId-1048313"></A>
If reporting a query evaluation problem, please be sure to include the sample XQuery code.</Body>
</XML>
